# Jeffrey Green

# Full-Stack Software Engineer | Finance Systems Analyst

Chicago, IL 708-979-5858

Email | Website | LinkedIn

Full-Stack Software Engineer with six years of professional experience developing strong interpersonal and communication skills, coupled with a proven ability to excel in a fast-paced, collaborative environment. A Software Engineer who's grown a passion for building and maintaining applications, automations, and scripts designed to improve processes and user experiences for the good of the company and the everyday user.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
- Libraries/Frameworks: Numpy, Pandas, Django, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, Bootstrap, Bulma
- Tools/Technologies: Git/Github, REST/RESTful APIs, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, sFTP Celigo, Postman
- Oracle Netsuite, Salesforce, PeopleSoft
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Microsoft Office / Google G Suite

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

#### **GROUP PROJECT - ELON MUSK'S TWITTER**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Flexbox, Node.js, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Authentication, Heroku, Netlify

• Reverse engineered a full-stack web application that utilizes full CRUD operations and user authentication/ authorization enabling users to create an account, post tweets, and like/comment on any user's tweets.

## **SOLO PROJECT - EXPLORE MARVEL UNIVERSE**

JavaScript, React, JSX, CSS, Flexbox, Responsive Design, RESTful API, MD5 Hash, Postman, Netlify

• Developed a modular and modern frontend React application fetching data from a third-party RESTful API.

## SOLO PROJECT - CAR COLLECTOR APP

Python, Django, PostgreSOL, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bulma, Responsive Design, Authentication, Netlify

• Full-stack web application with Python servers and SQL databases built with the full-featured framework Django and styled with the CSS framework, Bulma.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# PEAK6

Chicago, IL
Aug 2022 - Present

Finance Systems Analyst

- Develop and maintain automated tasks, data transformations, and/or scripts for the Finance team.
- Manage new systems implementations/integrations (banks, T&E, clearing firms, etc) and maintain multiple current system's functionality.
- Drive process improvements, correct failures in integration, and build automation by researching and testing new solutions involving scripting and mapping.
- End to end management of customizations, including scoping, requirement gathering, solution, architecting, development, testing and deployment.

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Remote

Mar 2022 - June 2022

Software Engineering Fellow

- Full-time 420+ hours, 12-week program.
- Developed and deployed full-stack applications with in-demand technologies.
- Practiced version control and collaborative software development with Git and GitHub.
- Safely modeled and stored data in SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Consumed and integrated third-party application programming interfaces (APIs) in an application.

## **CARS**

Chicago, IL

Digital Ad Production Specialist

Apr 2018 - Mar 2022

- Ensured customers' products are set live correctly and within turnaround time expectations by quickly and accurately inputting product and pricing data into online systems (PeopleSoft, Salesforce).
- Reviewed incoming contracts and enrollment documents for accuracy and compliance with standards.
- Worked with multiple partners in Operations, Finance, and Sales departments, handing off workflows for continuation & completion of enrollment.
- Thrived in a fast-paced environment, managing, keeping track of and progressing on multiple in-progress tasks.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp (June 2022)

## ROCKFORD UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Business Administration (May 2016)